Guide to the Hoyt family papers, 1828-1956.
Hoyt family papers,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Hoyt family papers, 1828-1956.
1812
2.1 cubic ft.; volumes; map case items.
Papers of the Hoyt family, including Civil War documentation and Jean Broughton Hoyt Smith's papers relating to her training as a nurse and her career as an interior decorator.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Scrapbooks, diaries, account books, address books, and other notebooks (40 volumes); correspondence, typescripts, notes, photographs and albums, diplomas and commissions, bills and receipts, newspaper clippings, and miscellaneous papers of Charles S. Hoyt of Potter, his daughter and son-in-law, Mr. and Mrs. Frederick Burroughs Smith of New York City, Clinton, and Utica, New York, and letters and scrapbooks of his other children, Charles S. Hoyt, Jr. and Agnes Barnum Hoyt; the correspondence, diaries, scrapbooks, and other papers of Charles S. Hoyt, Sr., relate to his activities as surgeon with the 126th and 39th Regiments, New York Volunteers, with whom he served in Maryland and Virginia during the Civil War; as New York State Assemblyman from Yates County (1853, 1867); and as secretary of the Board of Commissioners of Public Charities (1869+).
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Scrapbooks, diaries, account books, address books, and other notebooks (40 volumes); correspondence, typescripts, notes, photographs and albums, diplomas and commissions, bills and receipts, newspaper clippings, and miscellaneous papers of Charles S. Hoyt of Potter, his daughter and son-in-law, Mr. and Mrs. Frederick Burroughs Smith of New York City, Clinton, and Utica, New York, and letters and scrapbooks of his other children, Charles S. Hoyt, Jr. and Agnes Barnum Hoyt; the correspondence, diaries, scrapbooks, and other papers of Charles S. Hoyt, Sr., relate to his activities as surgeon with the 126th and 39th Regiments, New York Volunteers, with whom he served in Maryland and Virginia during the Civil War; as New York State Assemblyman from Yates County (1853, 1867); and as secretary of the Board of Commissioners of Public Charities (1869+).
Mrs. Jean Broughton Hoyt Smith's correspondence, manuscripts, scrapbooks, and other papers pertain to her training as a nurse at Bellevue Hospital (1902), her profession as an interior decorator, and other matters. Also, originals or copies of several letters to various members of the Hoyt family from or about Franklin Benjamin Sanborn and Charles James Folger, and a number of letters to Confederate soldiers from relatives and friends in Virginia, Georgia, Tennessee, and Florida describing conditions in the South as it was beset by Union forces.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Hoyt family.; Folger, Charles James, 1818-1884.; Hoyt, Agnes Barnum.; Hoyt, Charles S., Jr.; Hoyt, Charles S., 1822-1898.; Sanborn, F. B.(Franklin Benjamin), 1831-1917.; Smith, Frederick Burroughs.; Smith, Jean Broughton Hoyt.; Bellevue Hospital.; Board of Commissioners of Public Charities.; United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 39th (1861-1865); United States. Army. New York Infantry Regiment, 126th (1862-1865)
Subjects:
Interior decoration.; Nursing.; Public welfare.
Places:
New York (State)--Politics and government.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865--Medical care.
Form and Genre Terms:
Accounts.; Diaries.; Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Correspondence, 1839-1186 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, 1889-1908 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Correspondence, 1911-1920 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Correspondence, 1918 (Box 1, Folder 4-5)
- Correspondence, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Hoyt Family Research (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Genealogy: Bouton-Boughton 1350-1860 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Newsclippings primarily by/about Charles R. Hoyt, 1860's (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Jean Hoyt Smith Papers, 1828-1865 (Box 2, Folder 1-2)
- Transcript: Charles S. Hoyt Diary (Box 2, Folder 3-7)
- "A surgeon's Diary 1861-1865" by Hean Hoyt Smith (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Jean Hoyt Smith Manuscripts (Box 2, Folder 9-13)
- Journal: Jean Hoyt Smith [?]- Historical Notes (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Frank B. Sanborn: Correspondence by and about Sanborn, 1890-1951 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Drix Duryea, Inc., 1946 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Drix Duryea, Inc., 1947 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Louisa King, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Jean Hoyt Smith Manuscripts (Box 3, Folder 5-11)
- Newsclippings, 1946-1950 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Notebook: "Nova Scotia" [C. S. Hoyt?] (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Journals, Scrapbooks (Box 4)
- Diaries, Address Books (Box 5)
- Photographs, Photograph Albums (Box 6)
- Military Commission - New York State Volunteers, 1864 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Military Commission - New York State Volunteers, 1865 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- "Companion of the first Class ..." signed by Rutherford B. Hayes, 1889 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Diploma: Canandaigua Academy, 1890 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Certificate of appointment - State board of Charities, 1895 (Mapcase-folder 1)
- Photographs, Undated (Mapcase-folder 1)
- 10 Scrapbooks: Interior Decorating-related pictures, articles (Volume 1, 3-7, 9-12, 17)
- 1 Scrapbook: Magazine: newsclippings re: recipes, cooking, etc. (Volume 2)
- 1 Scrapbook: News clippings (Volume 13-14)
- 1 Scrapbook: Illustrations (Volume 15)
- 1 Scrapbook: Cornell (Volume 16)